
let questions = [

  {
      numb: 1,
      question: "Choose the right variant. Make up the sentence: children, like, play, to, football, many.",
      answer: "6,1,2,4,3,5",
      options: [
        "3,4,1,2,5,6",
        "3,2,5,1,4,6",
        "6,1,2,4,3,5",
        "5,3,1,4,2,6",
        "2,5,3,1,4,6"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 2,
      question: "Make up the sentence: project, very, is, interesting, this.",
      answer: "5,1,3,2,4",
      options: [,
        "3,2,5,1,4",
        "5,1,3,2,4",
        "3,4,1,2,5",
        "5,3,1,4,2",
        "2,5,3,1,4"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 3,
      question: "Choose the right variant in Present Perfect: We … bought a lot of flowers for our teacher.",
      answer: "have",
      options: [
        "has",
        "to have",
        "have to",
        "have",
        "has to"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 4,
      question: "Choose the right variant in Present Perfect: It’s five years since I…had a holiday.",
      answer: "have",
      options: [
        "have",
        "has",
        "had",
        "to have",
        "have to"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 5,
      question: "Choose the right variant in Present Perfect: Here’s my report I … finished it at last.",
      answer: "have",
      options: [
        "has",
        "had",
        "have",
        "to have",
        "have to"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 6,
      question: "Choose the right variant in Present Perfect: How many people … she invited?",
      answer: "has",
      options: [
        "have",
        "to have",
        "have to",
        "has",
        "has to"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 7,
      question: "Choose the right variant in Present Perfect: Our manager … gone to Almaty on business.",
      answer: "has",
      options: [
        "has",
        "to have",
        "have to",
        "have",
        "has to"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 8,
      question: "Make up the sentence: day, we, every, lessons, four, have.",
      answer: "2,6,5,4,3,1",
      options: [
        "5,6,3,1,4,2",
        "2,5,4,1,3,6",
        "2,6,5,4,3,1",
        "3,5,6,4,1,2",
        "5,2,3,1,4,6"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 9,
      question: "Make up the sentence: are, there, chairs, any, the, room, in?",
      answer: "1,2,4,3,7,5,6",
      options: [
        "2,5,3,7,4,1,6",
        "1,2,4,3,7,5,6",
        "4,2,5,7,2,3,6",
        "2,3,4,5,6,1,7",
        "2,6,3,5,4,7,1"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 10,
      question: "Make up the sentence: watch, TV, evening, every, we, don’t.",
      answer: "5,6,1,2,4,3",
      options: [
        "5,1,2,4,3,6",
        "1,5,3,6,2,4",
        "2,3,1,6,5,4",
        "5,6,1,2,4,3",
        "5,3,1,6,4,2"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 11,
      question: "Choose the right variant in Present Perfect: My parents ___ to the USA many times.",
      answer: "have been",
      options: [
        "had been",
        "have been",
        "were",
        "were",
        "will have been"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 12,
      question: "Choose the right variant in Present Perfect: We ____ a holiday since 1999.",
      answer: "haven’t had",
      options: [
        "hadn’t have",
        "don’t have",
        "haven’t had",
        "didn’t have",
        "won’t have"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 13,
      question: "Choose the right variant in Present Perfect: I ____ Peter this week.",
      answer: "haven’t seen",
      options: [
        "haven’t seen",
        "hadn’t seen",
        "won’t have seen",
        "didn’t see",
        "don’t see"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 14,
      question: "Choose the right variant in Present Perfect: Tom ___ a car recently.",
      answer: "has bought",
      options: [
        "bought",
        "has bought",
        "is bought",
        "had bought",
        "will have bought"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 15,
      question: "Choose the right sentence in Present Perfect:",
      answer: "At last I have done my homework",
      options: [
        "I have to go to my relatives",
        "They left office 5 minutes ago",
        "We are having dinner now",
        "At last I have done my homework",
        "He had gone home when I arrived at 11 o’clock"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 16,
      question: "Choose the right sentence in Present Perfect:",
      answer: "Has he decided what he must do",
      options: [
        "I have lectures every week",
        "Has he decided what he must do",
        "They didn’t have to do it",
        "He’ll have been in Britain by next Monday",
        "I remembered that I had left the passport"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 17,
      question: "Choose the right sentence in Present Perfect:",
      answer: "We haven’t discussed this matter yet",
      options: [
        "I had forgotten to mind my alarm-clock up",
        "They went to the university 5 min ago",
        "We haven’t discussed this matter yet",
        "She has to type letters",
        "I have some minutes to listen to you"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 18,
      question: "Choose the right sentence in Present Perfect:",
      answer: "Where is boss? He has just gone away",
      options: [
        "I have to receive important papers",
        "She’ll have come by that time",
        "My friend was very happy",
        "When I woke up it had been already 10 o’clock",
        "Where is boss? He has just gone away"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 19,
      question: "Make up the sentence: gets, she, to, the, by, University, the, metro.",
      answer: "2,1,3,4,6,5,7,8",
      options: [
        "2,5,3,7,4,6,4,8",
        "1,3,6,2,7,3,4",
        "2,1,3,4,6,5,7,8",
        "2,4,1,5,6,4,8,3",
        "4,1,2,3,8,2,5,6"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 20,
      question: "Choose the right variant: … elephant is too big.",
      answer: "the",
      options: [
        "these",
        "a",
        "those",
        "the",
        "…"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 21,
      question: "Choose the antonym: silence.",
      answer: "noise.",
      options: [
        "applaud.",
        "ship.",
        "noise.",
        "tree.",
        "shop."
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 22,
      question: "Choose the antonym: enemy.",
      answer: "friend.",
      options: [
        "friend.",
        "relative.",
        "neighbor.",
        "lawyer.",
        "student."
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 23,
      question: "Choose the antonym: tragedy.",
      answer: "comedy.",
      options: [
        "quarrel.",
        "comedy.",
        "cinema.",
        "soap.",
        "misunderstanding."
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 24,
      question: "Choose the right variant: I saw … in the library.",
      answer: "him.",
      options: [
        "myself.",
        "she.",
        "they.",
        "we.",
        "him."
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 25,
      question: "Choose the right variant: Your room is larger than ….",
      answer: "mine.",
      options: [
        "I.",
        "you.",
        "mine.",
        "she.",
        "he."
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 26,
      question: "Choose the right variant: You can translate this text….",
      answer: "yourself.",
      options: [
        "myself.",
        "ourselves.",
        "you.",
        "yourself.",
        "himself."
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 27,
      question: "Choose the right variant: My sister cooks breakfast for ….",
      answer: "us.",
      options: [
        "we.",
        "our.",
        "us.",
        "ours.",
        "hers."
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 28,
      question: "Choose the right variant: Tell me … address, please.",
      answer: "your.",
      options: [
        "you.",
        "yours.",
        "yourself.",
        "your.",
        "we."
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 29,
      question: "Choose the right variant: We must translate this text….",
      answer: "ourselves.",
      options: [
        "myself.",
        "yourself.",
        "himself.",
        "ourselves.",
        "herself."
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 30,
      question: "Choose the right variant: Strong families also speak about … problems.",
      answer: "their.",
      options: [
        "their.",
        "they.",
        "theirs.",
        "them.",
        "themselves."
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 31,
      question: "Choose the right variant: Asem has got … apple.",
      answer: "an.",
      options: [
        "a.",
        "some.",
        "an.",
        "the.",
        "…"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 32,
      question: "Choose the right variant: … room is too small.",
      answer: "the.",
      options: [
        "these.",
        "…",
        "a.",
        "the.",
        "those."
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 33,
      question: "Choose the right variant: The desk is in … corner of … room.",
      answer: "the/the.",
      options: [
        "…/the.",
        "the/the.",
        "the/a.",
        "a/a.",
        "a/the."
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 34,
      question: "Choose the right variant: Let’s go … home.",
      answer: "…",
      options: [
        "an.",
        "the.",
        "a.",
        "any.",
        "…"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 35,
      question: "Choose the right variant: January is … first month of … year.",
      answer: "the/the.",
      options: [
        "…/the.",
        "a/a.",
        "the/a.",
        "the/the.",
        "a/the."
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 36,
      question: "Choose the right variant: Where is … shop?",
      answer: "the.",
      options: [
        "an.",
        "…",
        "the.",
        "those.",
        "a."
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 37,
      question: "Choose the right variant: Please, close … window! It’s cold.",
      answer: "the.",
      options: [
        "these.",
        "the.",
        "…",
        "those.",
        "a."
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 38,
      question: "Choose the right variant: He was born in … 1945.",
      answer: "…",
      options: [
        "…",
        "the.",
        "a.",
        "an.",
        "those."
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 39,
      question: "Choose the right variant: (хотя) there is no pool, there is a nice garden.",
      answer: "although.",
      options: [
        "always.",
        "seldom.",
        "although.",
        "usually.",
        "often."
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 40,
      question: "Choose the right variant: Our classes begin … Monday.",
      answer: "on.",
      options: [
        "in.",
        "at.",
        "after.",
        "on.",
        "from."
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 41,
      question: "Choose the right variant: School year begins … the 1-st of September.",
      answer: "on.",
      options: [
        "into.",
        "in.",
        "after.",
        "on.",
        "by."
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 42,
      question: "Choose the right variant: We live ... Tole-bi street.",
      answer: "in.",
      options: [
        "at.",
        "to.",
        "in.",
        "on.",
        "under."
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 43,
      question: "Make up the sentence: are, they, my, relatives.",
      answer: "2,1,3,4",
      options: [
        "2,1,3,4",
        "3,1,4,2",
        "4,3,1,2",
        "2,4,1,3",
        "3,4,1,3"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 44,
      question: "Make up the sentence: where, you, live, do?",
      answer: "1,4,2,3",
      options: [
        "2,4,1,3",
        "4,2,1,3",
        "1,4,2,3",
        "3,1,4,2",
        "3,1,2,4"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 45,
      question: "Make up the sentence: she, does, English, learn?",
      answer: "2,1,4,3",
      options: [
        "1,4,3,2",
        "4,3,2,1",
        "3,4,1,3",
        "3,4,1,2",
        "2,1,4,3"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 46,
      question: "Choose the right variant: My father … fond of playing chess.",
      answer: "is",
      options: [
        "is",
        "am",
        "are",
        "be",
        "to be"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 47,
      question: "Choose the synonym: a time-table.",
      answer: "a schedule",
      options: [
        "homework",
        "current",
        "lecture",
        "a schedule",
        "lab"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 48,
      question: "Choose the synonym: spare-time.",
      answer: "free-time",
      options: [
        "never",
        "always",
        "seldom",
        "often",
        "free-time"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 49,
      question: "Choose the synonym: begin.",
      answer: "start",
      options: [
        "last",
        "past",
        "hang",
        "start",
        "stand"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 50,
      question: "Choose the synonym: finish.",
      answer: "end",
      options: [
        "spend",
        "end",
        "lend",
        "send",
        "sing"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 51,
      question: "Choose the synonym: huge.",
      answer: "enormous",
      options: [
        "nice",
        "interesting",
        "small",
        "enormous",
        "wonderful"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 52,
      question: "Choose the synonym: salary.",
      answer: "wages",
      options: [
        "hare",
        "wages",
        "money",
        "free",
        "trip"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 53,
      question: "Choose the antonym: truth.",
      answer: "lie",
      options: [
        "sock",
        "dream",
        "son",
        "lie",
        "spoon"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 54,
      question: "Choose the antonym: turn up.",
      answer: "turn down",
      options: [
        "turn down",
        "east",
        "autumn",
        "try on",
        "morning"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 55,
      question: "Choose the antonym: Sit down.",
      answer: "stand up",
      options: [
        "go out",
        "applaud",
        "stand up",
        "turn off",
        "shop"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 56,
      question: "Choose the antonym: get on.",
      answer: "get off",
      options: [
        "between",
        "get off",
        "over",
        "get home",
        "under"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 57,
      question: "Choose the antonym: get married.",
      answer: "get divorced",
      options: [
        "relative",
        "neighbor",
        "get divorced",
        "lawyer",
        "student"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 58,
      question: "Choose the antonym: turn off.",
      answer: "turn on",
      options: [
        "pick up",
        "take off",
        "try on",
        "pay back",
        "turn on"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 59,
      question: "Choose the right variant: Two thousand and twelve.",
      answer: "2012.",
      options: [
        "2112.",
        "2002.",
        "2012.",
        "2102.",
        "2201."
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 60,
      question: "Find the plural form of the word: mouse.",
      answer: "mice.",
      options: [
        "mouse.",
        "mouses.",
        "mousers.",
        "mice.",
        "mices."
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 61,
      question: "Choose the right variant: We…..lectures and tutorials every day.",
      answer: "have",
      options: [
        "are",
        "will have",
        "have",
        "to have",
        "is",
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 62,
      question: "Choose the right variant: It was Sunday and we … classes.",
      answer: "didn’t have",
      options: [
        "won’t have",
        "didn’t have",
        "don’t have",
        "shan’t have",
        "are not"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 63,
      question: "Choose the right answer: Is he sitting in the classroom?",
      answer: "Yes, he is",
      options: [
        "Yes, he will",
        "No, he doesn’t",
        "Yes, he does",
        "Yes, he is",
        "Yes, he did"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 64,
      question: "Choose the right answer: Do you like our University?",
      answer: "Yes, I do",
      options: [
        "No, she doesn’t",
        "No, I will not",
        "Yes, I do",
        "No, she hasn’t",
        "Yes, she will"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 65,
      question: "Choose the right answer: Does she go to the University?",
      answer: "Yes, she does",
      options: [
        "Yes, she does",
        "No, I shall not",
        "Yes, she will",
        "Yes, he will",
        "Yes, I have"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 66,
      question: "Choose the right answer: Have you a car?",
      answer: "Yes, I have",
      options: [
        "No, he hasn’t",
        "No, he doesn’t",
        "Yes, he will",
        "Yes, I have",
        "Yes, I shall"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 67,
      question: "Choose the right answer: Can you go to the cinema?",
      answer: "Yes, I can",
      options: [
        "Yes, I do",
        "No, I couldn’t",
        "Yes, I shall",
        "No, he will not",
        "Yes, I can",
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 68,
      question: "Choose the right variant: Strong families also speak about … problems.",
      answer: "their",
      options: [
        "theirs",
        "they",
        "them",
        "their",
        "themselves"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 69,
      question: "Find the plural form of the word “a wife”.",
      answer: "wives",
      options: [
        "a wives",
        "a wifes",
        "wifes",
        "wivs",
        "wives",
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 70,
      question: "Find the plural form of the word “a match”.",
      answer: "matches",
      options: [
        "a matchs",
        "matches",
        "matchs",
        "a matches",
        "match’s"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 71,
      question: "Find the plural form of the word “an address”.",
      answer: "addresses",
      options: [
        "addreses",
        "adreses",
        "address",
        "adreces",
        "addresses",
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 72,
      question: "Find the plural form of the word “an ox”.",
      answer: "oxen",
      options: [
        "oxes",
        "an oxen",
        "oxen",
        "oxs",
        "an oxes"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 73,
      question: "Choose the right variant: We have six lessons a day (usually).",
      answer: "We usually have six lessons a day",
      options: [
        "We have usually six lessons a day",
        "We usually have six lessons a day",
        "We have six lessons a day usually",
        "We have six usually lesson a day",
        "We have six lessons usually a day"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 74,
      question: "Choose the right variant: We drink tea in the morning (always).",
      answer: "We always drink tea in the morning",
      options: [
        "We drink tea in the morning always",
        "Always we always drink tea in the morning",
        "We always drink tea in the morning",
        "We drink tea in always the morning",
        "We drink in the morning tea always"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 75,
      question: "What part of speech is the underlined word? It is one of the best holidays for children.",
      answer: "adjective",
      options: [
        "adverb",
        "adjective",
        "verb",
        "noun",
        "pronoun"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 76,
      question: "Insert the right word: ... temperature.",
      answer: "to take",
      options: [
        "to mean",
        "to pressure",
        "to make",
        "to take",
        "to do"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 77,
      question: "Choose the appropriate word: What is your favourite….? Can you play it?",
      answer: "instrument",
      options: [
        "song",
        "dance",
        "instrument",
        "aria",
        "orchestra"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 78,
      question: "Express in a word: Fried pieces of potato.",
      answer: "Chips",
      options: [
        "Course",
        "Chips",
        "Toast",
        "Starter",
        "Crisp"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 79,
      question: "What part of speech is the underlined word? It is one of the best holidays for children.",
      answer: "noun",
      options: [
        "adverb",
        "verb",
        "pronoun",
        "adjective",
        "noun"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 80,
      question: "Choose the right variant: She …helps her mother (всегда).",
      answer: "always",
      options: [
        "yet",
        "already",
        "always",
        "seldom",
        "never"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 81,
      question: "Choose the right variant: Do you …go through the park (часто)?",
      answer: "often",
      options: [
        "often",
        "ever",
        "yet",
        "usually",
        "always",
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 82,
      question: "Choose the right variant: When do you … get up (обычно)?",
      answer: "usually",
      options: [
        "seldom",
        "sometimes",
        "usually",
        "often",
        "always"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 83,
      question: "Choose the right variant: She … takes medicine (часто).",
      answer: "often",
      options: [
        "never",
        "always",
        "sometimes",
        "often",
        "seldom"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 84,
      question: "Choose the right variant: Eleven thousand nine hundred and thirty-four.",
      answer: "11934",
      options: [
        "19134",
        "11334",
        "11934",
        "11134",
        "12349"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 85,
      question: "Choose the antonym: lazy.",
      answer: "hard-working",
      options: [
        "modern",
        "noisy",
        "far",
        "shy",
        "hard-working",
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 86,
      question: "Choose the antonym: boring.",
      answer: "interesting",
      options: [
        "far",
        "funny",
        "interesting",
        "noisy",
        "new"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 87,
      question: "Choose the antonym: lend.",
      answer: "borrow",
      options: [
        "sell",
        "borrow",
        "buy",
        "win",
        "do"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 88,
      question: "Choose the antonym: dangerous.",
      answer: "safe",
      options: [
        "old",
        "clean",
        "safe",
        "happy",
        "far"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 89,
      question: "Choose the right variant: “three hundred and seventy-five.”",
      answer: "375.",
      options: [
        "371",
        "3075.",
        "357.",
        "357.",
        "375."
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 90,
      question: "Choose the right variant: “three hundred and five.”",
      answer: "305.",
      options: [
        "3005.",
        "350.",
        "305.",
        "35.",
        "3050."
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 91,
      question: "Choose the right variant: There is (көп, много) snow in the streets.",
      answer: "much",
      options: [
        "many",
        "little",
        "a little",
        "much",
        "small"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 92,
      question: "Choose the right variant: “two thousand and five.”",
      answer: "2005.",
      options: [
        "2005.",
        "2050.",
        "2015.",
        "2025",
        "205.",
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 93,
      question: "Choose the right variant: менің әпкемнің достары. друзья моей сестры.",
      answer: "my sister’s friends.",
      options: [
        "my sisters’ friend.",
        "my sisters friend.",
        "my sister’s friends.",
        "my sisters’ friends.",
        "my sisters friends."
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 94,
      question: "Choose the right variant: Our classes begin … the morning.",
      answer: "in",
      options: [
        "on",
        "in",
        "at",
        "after",
        "from"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 95,
      question: "Choose the right variant: Sit …",
      answer: "down",
      options: [
        "up",
        "in",
        "after",
        "down",
        "by"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 96,
      question: "Choose the right variant: They will come … Tuesday.",
      answer: "on",
      options: [
        "in",
        "at",
        "on",
        "from",
        "after"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 97,
      question: "Choose the right variant: It’s a large building (артында, позади) a garden.",
      answer: "behind",
      options: [
        "with",
        "in",
        "on",
        "next to",
        "behind",
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 98,
      question: "Choose the right variant: There is a bedroom (үстінде, нthe second floor.",
      answer: "on",
      options: [
        "above",
        "on",
        "in",
        "of",
        "to"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 99,
      question: "Choose the right variant: The park is (аралығында, между) our house and the hostel.",
      answer: "between",
      options: [
        "near",
        "in front of",
        "between",
        "next to",
        "to the right of"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 100,
      question: "Find the plural form of the word: sheep.",
      answer: "sheep",
      options: [
        "sheeppes",
        "sheep",
        "sheeps",
        "sheepes",
        "sheepen"
      ]
    },
  {
    numb: 101,
    question: "Choose the right variant: I… to the teacher last week.",
    answer: "spoke",
    options: [
      "shall speak",
      "speak",
      "spoke",
      "speaks",
      "will speak",
    ]
  },
  
  {
    numb: 102,
    question: "Choose the right variant: When did he … home yesterday?",
    answer: "come",
    options: [
      "to come",
      "coming",
      "came",
      "comes",
      "come",
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 103,
    question: "Choose the right variant: He did not … his town last year.",
    answer: "visit",
    options: [
      "visits",
      "will visit",
      "visit",
      "visited",
      "to visit"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 104,
    question: "Choose the right variant: … for a walk.",
    answer: "to go",
    options: [
      "to have",
      "to go",
      "to do",
      "to meet",
      "to see",
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 105,
    question: "Choose the right variant: … you have breakfast in the kitchen?",
    answer: "do",
    options: [
      "has",
      "do",
      "does",
      "have",
      "had",
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 106,
    question: "Choose the right variant: …. we go to the cinema yesterday?",
    answer: "did",
    options: [
      "does",
      "is",
      "did",
      "do",
      "were"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 107,
    question: "Choose the right variant: She is as …. as her mother.",
    answer: "nice",
    options: [
      "more nice",
      "nice",
      "nicest",
      "nicer",
      "the nicest"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 108,
    question: "Choose the right variant: This building is as….as the one in our street.",
    answer: "expensive",
    options: [
      "expensiver",
      "more expensive",
      "expensive",
      "expensivest",
      "most expensive"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 109,
    question: "Choose the right variant: The brown suit is as… as the black one.",
    answer: "cheap",
    options: [
      "cheaper",
      "cheap",
      "cheapest",
      "more cheap",
      "cheapier"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 110,
    question: "Choose the right variant: Kazakhstan is … than France.",
    answer: "larger",
    options: [
      "the largest",
      "more large",
      "most large",
      "larger",
      "large"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 111,
    question: "Choose the right variant: Oranges are … than apples.",
    answer: "more expensive",
    options: [
      "expensive",
      "most expensive",
      "expensiver",
      "expensivest",
      "more expensive"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 112,
    question: "Find the plural form of the word: fish.",
    answer: "fish",
    options: [
      "fishs",
      "fishees",
      "fish",
      "fishes",
      "fishing"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 113,
    question: "Choose the right variant: You know Kazakh … than your father.",
    answer: "worse",
    options: [
      "the worst",
      "badly",
      "badder",
      "more worse",
      "worse"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 114,
    question: "Choose the right variant: Paris is … than London.",
    answer: "more beautiful",
    options: [
      "beautifuler",
      "much beautiful",
      "more beautiful",
      "most beautiful",
      "much most beautiful"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 115,
    question: "Choose the right variant: The Aral is … sea in the world.",
    answer: "the smallest",
    options: [
      "small",
      "the smallest",
      "more small",
      "smaller",
      "the most small"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 116,
    question: "Choose the right answer: словарь студента. білімгердің сөздігі.",
    answer: "the student's dictionary.",
    options: [
      "the students dictionary.",
      "the student's dictionary.",
      "the students’ dictionary.",
      "the student dictionaries.",
      "the students dictionaries"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 117,
    question: "Choose the right answer: отец моего друга. менің досымның әкесі.",
    answer: "my friend’s father.",
    options: [
      "my friends’ father.",
      "my friend’ father.",
      "my friend’s father.",
      "my friends father.",
      "my friends father."
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 118,
    question: "Choose the right variant: детский магазин. балалар дүкені.",
    answer: "children’s shop.",
    options: [
      "children shop.",
      "childrens’ shop.",
      "children’s shop.",
      "childrens shops.",
      "shop of children."
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 119,
    question: "Choose the right translation: второй.",
    answer: "the second.",
    options: [
      "the second.",
      "the third.",
      "two.",
      "twelve.",
      "twenty."
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 120,
    question: "Choose the right variant: Would you like … cup of coffee?",
    answer: "a",
    options: [
      "an",
      "the",
      "some",
      "a",
      "–"
    ]
  },
  
  
  {
    numb: 121,
    question: "Choose the right translation: седьмой.",
    answer: "the seventh.",
    options: [
      "the seventh.",
      "seven.",
      "seventy.",
      "seventeen.",
      "eight"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 122,
    question: "Choose the right translation: двадцать первый.",
    answer: "the twenty first.",
    options: [
      "twenty two.",
      "the twentieth.",
      "twelve.",
      "the twenty first.",
      "thirty."
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 123,
    question: "Choose the right translation: двадцать третий.",
    answer: "the twenty third.",
    options: [
      "the twenty second.",
      "the twentieth.",
      "the twenty third.",
      "the twenty first.",
      "twenty."
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 124,
    question: "Choose the right variant: The students... twice a year.",
    answer: "take exams",
    options: [
      "is taking an exam",
      "take exams",
      "enter the institute",
      "hold lectures",
      "carries out research"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 125,
    question: "Choose the right variant: There are … letters in the English alphabet.",
    answer: "26",
    options: [
      "26",
      "27",
      "23",
      "24",
      "28"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 126,
    question: "Find the plural form of the word: mother-in-law.",
    answer: "mothers-in-law",
    options: [
      "mother-ins-law",
      "motheres-in-law",  
      "mothers-in-law",
      "mother-in-laws",
      "mother-in-law"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 127,
    question: "Find the plural form of the word: goose.",
    answer: "geese",
    options: [
      "geese",
      "geeses",
      "goosees",
      "goose",
      "goozes"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 128,
    question: "Choose the right variant: Where do we keep our clothes?",
    answer: "in a wardrobe",
    options: [
      "in a basin",
      "in a wardrobe",
      "in a shelf",
      "in a bookcase",
      "on a bed"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 129,
    question: "Choose the right variant: Where do we have guests?",
    answer: "in the sitting-room",
    options: [
      "in the bedroom",
      "in the kitchen",
      "in the sitting-room",
      "in the bathroom",
      "in the nursery"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 130,
    question: "Find the plural form of the word: man.",
    answer: "men",
    options: [
      "menes",
      "mens",
      "manes",
      "mans",
      "men"
    ]
  },
  
  {
    numb: 131,
    question: "Choose the right variant: “three hundred and sixty five”.",
    answer: "365",
    options: [
      "3065",
      "356",
      "365",
      "361",
      "35"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 132,
    question: "Choose the right variant: to be independent.",
    answer: "тәуелсіз болу. /быть независимым",
    options: [
      "талғаусыз болу. /быть безразличным",
      "тәуелсіз болу. /быть независимым",
      "тәуелді болу. /быть зависимым",
      "қызығушылық таныту. /быть заинтересованным",
      "белсенді болу. /быть активным"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 133,
    question: "Choose the right variant: to be angry with smb.",
    answer: "біреуге ашулану. /сердиться на кого-либо",
    options: [
      "біреуді жек көру. /ненавидеть кого-либо",
      "біреуге қатысты болу. /относиться к кому-либо",
      "біреуге ашулану. /сердиться на кого-либо",
      "біреумен күресу. /бороться с кем-либо",
      "біреуді мақтан ету./ гордиться кем-либо"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 134,
    question: "Choose the right variant: “three hundred and three”.",
    answer: "303",
    options: [
      "303",
      "330",
      "3003",
      "33",
      "3030"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 135,
    question: "Choose the right variant: “two thousand and seven”.",
    answer: "2007",
    options: [
      "207",
      "2070",
      "2017",
      "2007",
      "2027"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 136,
    question: "Choose the right variant: … lessons do you have every day?",
    answer: "how many",
    options: [
      "who",
      "how many",
      "how much",
      "where",
      "why"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 137,
    question: "Choose the right variant: … butter is there in the fridge?",
    answer: "how much",
    options: [
      "who",
      "what",
      "how much",
      "where",
      "why"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 138,
    question: "Choose the right variant: The country that you were born in is …",
    answer: "motherland",
    options: [
      "abroad",
      "virgin land",
      "village",
      "motherland",
      "city"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 139,
    question: "Choose the right answer: … does it cost to stay at the Hilton hotel?",
    answer: "how much",
    options: [
      "how many",
      "where",
      "how much",
      "how long",
      "when"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 140,
    question: "Choose the right answer: … would you like to drink?",
    answer: "what",
    options: [
      "whose",
      "how",
      "what",
      "how many",
      "how much"
    ]
  },
  
  
  {
    numb: 141,
    question: "Choose the right variant. ... a shower.",
    answer: "to have",
    options: [
      "to wake up",
      "to have",
      "to read",
      "to dress",
      "to sleep"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 142,
    question: "Choose the right answer. Where did you ... for your holiday last summer?",
    answer: "go",
    options: [
      "went",
      "go",
      "will go",
      "gone",
      "going"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 143,
    question: "Choose the right translation: двадцать седьмой.",
    answer: "the twenty seventh.",
    options: [
      "he seventh.",
      "the twentieth.",
      "the twenty seventh.",
      "twenty seven.",
      "the thirty sixth."
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 144,
    question: "Choose the right translation: сорок первый.",
    answer: "the fourty first.",
    options: [
      "forty.",
      "forty one.",
      "the fifty fourth.",
      "fourteen.",
      "the fourty first."
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 145,
    question: "Choose the right translation: двадцать пятый.",
    answer: "the twenty fifth.",
    options: [
      "twenty five.",
      "the twenty third.",
      "the twenty fifth.",
      "twelve.",
      "twenty one."
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 146,
    question: "Choose the right translation: девяносто девятый.",
    answer: "the ninety ninth.",
    options: [
      "ninety.",
      "ninety nine.",
      "nine",
      "ninetieth.",
      "the ninety ninth."
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 147,
    question: "Find the alternative question: The bed is in the bedroom.",
    answer: "Is the bed in the bedroom or in the living room?",
    options: [
      "Where is the bed?",
      "Is the bed in the bedroom or in the living room?",
      "Is it in the bedroom?",
      "What is it?",
      "Is it in the living room?"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 148,
    question: "Find the alternative question: She is a doctor.",
    answer: "Is she a doctor or a driver?",
    options: [
      "What is she?",
      "Is she a doctor?",
      "Is she a doctor or a driver?",
      "Who is she?",
      "Where is she?"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 149,
    question: "Choose the right variant. I met my … friend yesterday.",
    answer: "best",
    options: [
      "better",
      "best",
      "goodest",
      "the most best",
      "the good"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 150,
    question: "Choose the right variant. What is that ring made …?",
    answer: "of",
    options: [
      "with",
      "in",
      "from",
      "of",
      "away"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 151,
    question: "Choose the right variant. He … looking for a new job at the moment.",
    answer: "is",
    options: [
      "will be",
      "is",
      "was",
      "are",
      "were"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 152,
    question: "Choose the right variant. Listen! Somebody … singing.",
    answer: "is",
    options: [
      "were",
      "am",
      "are",
      "was",
      "is"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 153,
    question: "Choose the right variant. I … watching TV when she entered the room.",
    answer: "was",
    options: [
      "am",
      "is",
      "was",
      "were",
      "shall be"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 154,
    question: "Choose the right variant. It … snowing when I got up.",
    answer: "was",
    options: [
      "was",
      "is",
      "were",
      "are",
      "will be"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 155,
    question: "Choose the right variant. I … looking for a new flat at the moment.",
    answer: "am",
    options: [
      "was",
      "is",
      "am",
      "are",
      "were"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 156,
    question: "Choose the right variant. We are at home. We … not working at the moment.",
    answer: "are",
    options: [
      "are",
      "was",
      "is",
      "were",
      "shall be"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 157,
    question: "Choose the right variant. I … going to the library now.",
    answer: "am",
    options: [
      "is",
      "are",
      "am",
      "was",
      "we"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 158,
    question: "Choose the right variant. What … Tom doing now?",
    answer: "is",
    options: [
      "are",
      "was",
      "were",
      "is",
      "will be"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 159,
    question: "Choose the right variant. I … visit my grandmother at 3 o’clock tomorrow.",
    answer: "shall",
    options: [
      "am",
      "was",
      "shall",
      "were",
      "is"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 160,
    question: "Find the disjunctive question:",
    answer: "You are a student, aren’t you?",
    options: [
      "Were they reading a letter?",
      "Did he study history in 1960?",
      "You are a student, aren’t you?",
      "How well does he speak German?",
      "Have you a flat or a room?"
    ]
  },
  
  {
    numb: 161,
    question: "Find the disjunctive question:",
    answer: "They did not go there yesterday, did they?",
    options: [
      "Why does she eat so little?",
      "Who teaches you English?",
      "How many pencils do you need?",
      "Are you a student or a teacher?",
      "They did not go there yesterday, did they?"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 162,
    question: "Find the disjunctive question:",
    answer: "He has a family, hasn’t he?",
    options: [
      "Which book do you like?",
      "Have you seen this film?",
      "He has a family, hasn’t he?",
      "Whom do you meet at the club?",
      "Will you help me?"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 163,
    question: "Find the disjunctive question:",
    answer: "She is well, isn’t she?",
    options: [
      "Was he skiing at this time yesterday?",
      "She is well, isn’t she?",
      "Is she skating now?",
      "What do you like?",
      "Have you got any sisters or brothers?"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 164,
    question: "Find the alternative question: The chair is in the bedroom.",
    answer: "Is the chair in the bedroom or in the living room?",
    options: [
      "Where is the chair?",
      "Is it in the bedroom?",
      "Is the chair in the bedroom or in the living room?",
      "What is it?",
      "Is it in the living room?"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 165,
    question: "Find the alternative question: She is a teacher.",
    answer: "Is she a teacher or a doctor?",
    options: [
      "Is she a teacher or a doctor?",
      "Is she a teacher?",
      "What is she?",
      "Who is she?",
      "Where is she?"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 166,
    question: "Find the alternative question: We are going to the picnic.",
    answer: "Are we going to the picnic or to the theatre?",
    options: [
      "We are going to the picnic, aren’t we?",
      "Are we going to the picnic?",
      "Are we going to the picnic or to the theatre?",
      "Are we going to the theatre?",
      "Where do we go?"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 167,
    question: "Find the alternative question: Arman is writing the dictation.",
    answer: "Is Arman writing the dictation or composition?",
    options: [
      "Arman is writing the dictation, isn’t he?",
      "Does Arman write the dictation?",
      "Did Arman write the dictation?",
      "Is Arman writing the dictation?",
      "Is Arman writing the dictation or composition?"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 168,
    question: "Find the alternative question: I get up at 7 o’clock every day.",
    answer: "Do I get up at 7 o’clock or at 8 o’clock every day?",
    options: [
      "I get up at 7 o’clock, don’t I?",
      "Did I get up at 7 o’clock?",
      "Do I get up at 7 o’clock or at 8 o’clock every day?",
      "Do I get up at 7 o’clock?",
      "Have I got up at 7 o’clock?"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 169,
    question: "Find the alternative question: My mother is cooking now.",
    answer: "Is my mother cooking or looking at the picture now?",
    options: [
      "Is my mother cooking now?",
      "Is my mother cooking or looking at the picture now?",
      "My mother is cooking now, isn’t she?",
      "Does my mother cook?",
      "My mother cooks, doesn’t she?"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 170,
    question: "Choose the right variant. Take an umbrella. It … raining.",
    answer: "is",
    options: [
      "was",
      "shall be",
      "is",
      "are",
      "were"
    ]
  },
  
  {
    numb: 171,
    question: "Choose the right variant. What … you doing at 11.30 yesterday?",
    answer: "were",
    options: [
      "are",
      "is",
      "were",
      "was",
      "shall be"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 172,
    question: "Choose the right variant. I’m getting … and ….",
    answer: "fatter/fatter",
    options: [
      "fat/fat",
      "more fat/fat",
      "the fattest/the fattest",
      "fatter/fatter",
      "the most fat/fat"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 173,
    question: "Choose the right variant. Stop …. our lesson isn’t over.",
    answer: "talking",
    options: [
      "speaking",
      "saying",
      "talking",
      "talked",
      "said"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 174,
    question: "Choose the Present Continuous tense.",
    answer: "they are writing a test",
    options: [
      "they wrote a test",
      "they will be writing a test",
      "they can write a test",
      "they have written a test",
      "they are writing a test"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 175,
    question: "Choose the right variant. She works six … on Saturday.",
    answer: "hours",
    options: [
      "o’clock",
      "hours",
      "hour",
      "watches",
      "minutes"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 176,
    question: "Choose the correct translation of the word: “соңғы курс білімгері, студент выпускник”.",
    answer: "a final year student",
    options: [
      "a first year student",
      "a second year student",
      "a final year student",
      "a freshman",
      "a sophomore"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 177,
    question: "Choose the right variant. I am a first – year student of the philological …",
    answer: "department",
    options: [
      "hostel",
      "department",
      "classes",
      "dean",
      "institution"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 178,
    question: "Choose the right variant. Our classes begin…",
    answer: "at half past 8",
    options: [
      "at night",
      "in two years",
      "yesterday",
      "next month",
      "at half past 8"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 179,
    question: "Choose the antonym. «boring»:",
    answer: "interesting",
    options: [
      "friendly",
      "interesting",
      "shy",
      "lazy",
      "mean"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 180,
    question: "Choose the antonym. «lazy»:",
    answer: "hard-working",
    options: [
      "mean",
      "talkative",
      "hard-working",
      "generous",
      "shy"
    ]
  },
  
  
  {
    numb: 181,
    question: "Choose the antonym. «friendly»:",
    answer: "unfriendly",
    options: [
      "shy",
      "generous",
      "lazy",
      "unfriendly",
      "mean"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 182,
    question: "Choose the right question: She watches TV in the evening.",
    answer: "what does she do in the evening?",
    options: [
      "where does she watch tv?",
      "when does she get up?",
      "what does she do in the evening?",
      "what do you do in the evening?",
      "what does he do in the evening?"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 183,
    question: "Choose the negative form: She makes a report for the conference.",
    answer: "She does not make a report for the conference",
    options: [
      "Does she not make a report for the conference",
      "She does not make a report for the conference",
      "She not does make a report for the conference",
      "She did not make a report for the conference",
      "She makes not a report for the conference"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 184,
    question: "Choose the right variant. She lives not … from the institute.",
    answer: "far",
    options: [
      "about",
      "early",
      "far",
      "easy",
      "above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 185,
    question: "Choose the right preposition. It takes him … 5 minutes to get… the institute.",
    answer: "…, to",
    options: [
      "…, to",
      "on, …",
      "to, to",
      "to, …",
      "on, to"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 186,
    question: "Choose the right variant. do, cinema, when, to, you, the , go.",
    answer: "when do you go to the cinema?",
    options: [
      "when go you do to the cinema?",
      "when go you to the cinema do?",
      "when do you go to the cinema?",
      "do you go to the cinema?",
      "do you do the cinema?"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 187,
    question: "Define the right tense form. I am looking the key:",
    answer: "present continuous",
    options: [
      "present simple",
      "past continuous",
      "future simple",
      "past simple",
      "present continuous"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 188,
    question: "Choose the right answer. When do you get up?",
    answer: "I get up at 7 o` clock",
    options: [
      "I live in Taraz",
      "I study at the institute",
      "I entered the institute",
      "I get up at 7 o` clock",
      "I don’t get up"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 189,
    question: "Choose the right question. I went to the party.",
    answer: "where did you go?",
    options: [
      "where did they go?",
      "where did you go?",
      "where do you go?",
      "where do they go?",
      "where does he go?"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 190,
    question: "Choose the right variant. “… it snow yesterday?”",
    answer: "did it rain yesterday?",
    options: [
      "were it rain yesterday?",
      "does it rain yesterday?",
      "did it rained yesterday?",
      "did it rain yesterday?",
      "is it rained yesterday?"
    ]
  }, 
  
  
  {
    numb: 191,
    question: "Complete the sentence. Does your mother feel…",
    answer: "tired",
    options: [
      "interest",
      "important",
      "tired",
      "heart",
      "nice"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 192,
    question: "Choose the right variant. It is never late to learn.",
    answer: "ештен кеш жақсы. /никогда не поздно учиться",
    options: [
      "жылтырағанның бәрі алтын емес. /не все золото,что блестит",
      "ештен кеш жақсы. /никогда не поздно учиться",
      "өз үйім өлең төсегім./в гостях хорошо, но дома лучше",
      "отан оттан да ыстық. /лучше поздно,чем никогда",
      "еңбек түбі зейнет./знать все-знать ничего"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 193,
    question: "Choose the right variant. What do we call all the professors, lecturers and assistants?",
    answer: "a teaching staff",
    options: [
      "the rector’s office",
      "an academician",
      "a teaching staff",
      "a teaching block",
      "lectures"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 194,
    question: "Choose the right variant. What do we call a 1st year student?",
    answer: "a freshman",
    options: [
      "a freshman",
      "a graduate",
      "an undergraduate",
      "a beginner",
      "researcher"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 195,
    question: "Choose the right translation. To be founded.",
    answer: "құрылу/ быть основанным",
    options: [
      "табылу/ быть известным",
      "танымал болу /быть найденным",
      "құрылу/ быть основанным",
      "сүйікті болу/быть любимым",
      "қабілетті болу /быть обнаруженным"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 196,
    question: "Choose the right translation. To be situated.",
    answer: "орналасу/ находиться",
    options: [
      "ашулану /рассердиться",
      "танымал болу /быть известным",
      "құрылу /быть основанным",
      "орналасу/ находиться",
      "танымал болмау /быть неизвестным"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 197,
    question: "Choose the right translation. To be good at.",
    answer: "қабілетті болу /быть способным к чему либо",
    options: [
      "жақсы болу /быть хорошим",
      "икемді болу /хорошо относиться",
      "қабілетті болу /быть способным к чему либо",
      "бай болу /быть богатым",
      "мейірімді болу /быть добрым"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 198,
    question: "Choose the right translation: To pay attention.",
    answer: "көңіл аудару /обращать внимание",
    options: [
      "ескерту жасау /записывать",
      "ескертуді қабылдау /принимать замечания",
      "көңіл аудару /обращать внимание",
      "лекция тыңдау /делать замечания",
      "лекция оқу/слушать лекцию"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 199,
    question: "Choose the right question. I went to the post office.",
    answer: "where did you go?",
    options: [
      "where do they go?",
      "where did you go?",
      "where do you go?",
      "where did they go?",
      "where does he go?"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 200,
    question: "Choose the right variant. The party wasn’t very good, so we …. long.",
    answer: "didn’t stay",
    options: [
      "aren’t stay",
      "won’t stay",
      "didn’t stay",
      "don’t stay",
      "doesn’t stay"
    ]
  },
  
  {
    numb: 201,
    question: "Choose the right variant. “… it rain yesterday?”",
    answer: "did it rain yesterday?",
    options: [
      "does it rain yesterday?",
      "did it rained yesterday?",
      "were it rain yesterday?",
      "did it rain yesterday?",
      "is it rained yesterday?"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 202,
    question: "Choose the right variant. It was very warm, so I …. a window.",
    answer: "opened",
    options: [
      "will open",
      "opened",
      "opens",
      "opening",
      "open"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 203,
    question: "Choose the right variant. She had a pen but she … any paper.",
    answer: "didn’t have",
    options: [
      "had",
      "has",
      "doesn’t have",
      "don’t have",
      "didn’t have"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 204,
    question: "Choose the right variant. The accident … last Sunday afternoon.",
    answer: "happened",
    options: [
      "happens",
      "happening",
      "happened",
      "happen",
      "will happen"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 205,
    question: "Choose the right variant. We … our holiday last year.",
    answer: "enjoyed",
    options: [
      "enjoys",
      "enjoying",
      "will enjoy",
      "enjoyed",
      "enjoy",
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 206,
    question: "Make up the sentence with these words: study, do, what, higher, school, at, you?",
    answer: "what higher school do you study at?",
    options: [
      "do you study at higher school?",
      "what do you higher school study at?",
      "what higher school do you study at?",
      "what do higher school you study at?",
      "what you do study at higher school?"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 207,
    question: "Put the correct form of the verb. Yesterday morning Helen … at 7 o’ clock.",
    answer: "woke up",
    options: [
      "woke up",
      "is waking up",
      "will wake up",
      "wakes up",
      "was waking up"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 208,
    question: "Define the right tense form. I am cutting the grass.",
    answer: "present continuous",
    options: [
      "present simple",
      "past continuous",
      "present continuous",
      "past simple",
      "future simple"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 209,
    question: "Make up the sentence with these words: do, what, Sunday, you, last, did?",
    answer: "what did you do last sunday?",
    options: [
      "what you do last sunday?",
      "what did you do last sunday?",
      "what do you did last sunday?",
      "what last sunday did you do?",
      "what do you last did sunday?"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 210,
    question: "Complete the sentence. The students of our university… several foreign languages.",
    answer: "learn",
    options: [
      "is learnt",
      "learning",
      "learn",
      "was learning",
      "is learning"
    ]
  },
  
  {
      numb: 211,
      question: "Make up the sentence with these words: school, did, when, start, you?",
      answer: "when did you start school?",
      options: [
          "when you did start school?",
          "when you start school?",
          "when school did you start?",
          "did you start school?",
          "when did you start school?"
      ]
  },
  {
      numb: 212,
      question: "Define the right tense form. He went to Almaty last week.",
      answer: "past simple",
      options: [
          "present simple",
          "past continuous",
          "past simple",
          "present continuous",
          "future simple"
      ]
  },
  {
      numb: 213,
      question: "Define the right tense form. They were writing a test at that time yesterday.",
      answer: "past continuous",
      options: [
          "present continuous",
          "past simple",
          "past continuous",
          "present simple",
          "future simple"
      ]
  },
  {
      numb: 214,
      question: "Define the right tense form. They clean the streets every day.",
      answer: "present simple",
      options: [
          "past continuous",
          "present simple",
          "present continuous",
          "past simple",
          "future simple"
      ]
  },
  {
      numb: 215,
      question: "Define the right tense form. He invited me to the party.",
      answer: "past simple",
      options: [
          "past simple",
          "present continuous",
          "present simple",
          "past continuous",
          "future simple"
      ]
  },
  {
      numb: 216,
      question: "Define the right tense form. They will discuss this question at this time tomorrow.",
      answer: "future simple",
      options: [
          "past simple",
          "present continuous",
          "future simple",
          "past continuous",
          "present simple"
      ]
  },
  {
      numb: 217,
      question: "Choose the right preposition. What kind of sport do you go __ __?",
      answer: "in, for",
      options: [
          "with, for",
          "out, of",
          "at, for",
          "for, in",
          "in, for"
      ]
  },
  {
      numb: 218,
      question: "Choose the right preposition. He has … time.",
      answer: "much",
      options: [
          "big",
          "many",
          "much",
          "more",
          "bigger",
      ]
  },
  
  
  {
    numb: 219,
    question: "Choose the right variant: я закончила школу в прошлом году. мен мектепті өткен жылы бітірдім.",
    answer: "I finished school last year",
    options: [
      "I did go to school last year",
      "I finished school last year",
      "I went to school last year",
      "I start school last year",
      "I last went year to school year"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 218,
    question: "Choose the right variant: … is your sister? She is a secretary.",
    answer: "what",
    options: [
      "why",
      "what",
      "who",
      "where",
      "when"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 219,
    question: "Choose the right variant: Cіз мына кітапты қайдан сатып алдыңыз? Где вы купили эту книгу?",
    answer: "where did you buy this book?",
    options: [
      "where you bought this book",
      "did you where buy this book?",
      "where you this book bought?",
      "where did you buy this book?",
      "where you did you buy this book?"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 220,
    question: "Choose the right variant: Kез-келген студент осы сұраққа жауап бере алады. Любой студент может ответить на этот вопрос.",
    answer: "Any student can answer this question",
    options: [
      "Some students must answer this question",
      "Many students must answer this question",
      "Any student can answer this question",
      "Can any student answer this question?",
      "Some students cannot answer this question"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 221,
    question: "Choose the right variant: What text …you translate yesterday?",
    answer: "did",
    options: [
      "did",
      "do",
      "have",
      "were",
      "are"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 222,
    question: "Choose the right variant: … time is it?",
    answer: "what",
    options: [
      "how",
      "what",
      "why",
      "where",
      "when"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 223,
    question: "Choose the right variant: It’s the… job he is ever had to do.",
    answer: "worst",
    options: [
      "bad",
      "badly",
      "worst",
      "worse",
      "as bad as"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 224,
    question: "Choose the right answer: What do you do?",
    answer: "I am a student",
    options: [
      "I’m helen",
      "I am a student",
      "fine, thanks",
      "I am working",
      "that was terrible"
    ]
  },
  
  {
    numb: 225,
    question: "Choose the right variant: ...queen visited a new hospital this morning.",
    answer: "the",
    options: [
      "__",
      "his",
      "her",
      "a",
      "the"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 226,
    question: "Choose the right synonym: “good”.",
    answer: "nice",
    options: [
      "better",
      "warm",
      "nice",
      "bad",
      "worse"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 227,
    question: "Choose the right variant: I can speak English ___ than you.",
    answer: "better",
    options: [
      "better",
      "more good",
      "well",
      "the best",
      "good"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 228,
    question: "Choose the right variant: He is ___ intelligent than I am.",
    answer: "more",
    options: [
      "very",
      "is more",
      "more",
      "most",
      "well"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 229,
    question: "Choose the right variant: He …at the theatre yesterday.",
    answer: "was",
    options: [
      "was",
      "were",
      "are",
      "is",
      "will be"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 230,
    question: "Choose the right variant: They … at home next weekend.",
    answer: "will be",
    options: [
      "is",
      "am",
      "will be",
      "are",
      "be"
    ]
  },
  
  
  {
    numb: 231,
    question: "Choose the right variant: We … this film last Monday.",
    answer: "watched",
    options: [
      "watching",
      "watched",
      "watch",
      "is watching",
      "will watch"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 232,
    question: "Choose the right variant: When my grandmother … young, she… an actress.",
    answer: "was/was",
    options: [
      "was/was",
      "was/were",
      "was/is",
      "is/was",
      "were/were"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 233,
    question: "Choose the right variant: My sister’s husband is my…",
    answer: "brother-in-law",
    options: [
      "cousin",
      "father",
      "brother-in-law",
      "uncle",
      "nephew"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 234,
    question: "Choose the right variant: My sister’s son is my…",
    answer: "nephew",
    options: [
      "uncle",
      "cousin",
      "brother",
      "nephew",
      "grandson"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 235,
    question: "Choose the right variant: My mother’s father is my…",
    answer: "grandfather",
    options: [
      "cousin",
      "brother",
      "grandfather",
      "uncle",
      "grandson"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 236,
    question: "Choose the right variant: My brother’s wife is my…",
    answer: "sister-in-law",
    options: [
      "aunt",
      "cousin",
      "grandmother",
      "daughter",
      "sister-in-law"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 237,
    question: "Choose the right variant: My sister’s daughter is my…",
    answer: "niece",
    options: [
      "sister-in-law",
      "niece",
      "sister",
      "cousin",
      "granddaughter"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 238,
    question: "Choose the right variant: My parents’ parents are my…",
    answer: "grandparents",
    options: [
      "grandmothers",
      "sister-in-law",
      "granddaughter",
      "grandparents",
      "grandchildren"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 239,
    question: "Choose the right variant: This is … winter for 20 years.",
    answer: "the worst",
    options: [
      "worst",
      "the more bad",
      "worse",
      "the worst",
      "bad"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 240,
    question: "Choose the right variant: Plants like … light.",
    answer: "much",
    options: [
      "much",
      "many",
      "a few",
      "few",
      "little",
    ]
  },
  
  
  {
    numb: 241,
    question: "Choose the right variant: Can you speak …foreign languages?",
    answer: "any",
    options: [
      "this",
      "some",
      "a",
      "much",
      "any",
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 242,
    question: "Choose the right variant: Please, clean… blackboard.",
    answer: "the",
    options: [
      "any",
      "the",
      "much",
      "this",
      "some",
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 243,
    question: "Choose the right variant: Are there … students in the reading room?",
    answer: "any",
    options: [
      "no",
      "some",
      "this",
      "any",
      "more",
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 244,
    question: "Complete the sentence. He is having breakfast now, …?",
    answer: "isn't he",
    options: [
      "is he",
      "isn't he",
      "hasn't he",
      "does he",
      "didn't he"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 245,
    question: "Choose the right variant. Did Julia phone you earlier?",
    answer: "yes, she did",
    options: [
      "yes, she do",
      "yes, she didn’t",
      "yes, she did",
      "yes, she does",
      "yes, she had"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 246,
    question: "Choose the right variant. Do you like hot tea?",
    answer: "yes, I do",
    options: [
      "yes, I’d like",
      "yes, I will",
      "yes, I like",
      "yes, I do",
      "yes, I did"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 247,
    question: "Complete the sentence. Our boys are playing well, …?",
    answer: "aren’t they",
    options: [
      "are they",
      "have they",
      "aren’t they",
      "was they",
      "isn’t they"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 248,
    question: "Choose the right variant. We are waiting for you, ….",
    answer: "aren’t we?",
    options: [
      "aren’t we?",
      "will you?",
      "don’t you?",
      "do you?",
      "are we?"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 249,
    question: "Choose the right form of the verb “to have”: She … a good weekend.",
    answer: "has",
    options: [
      "have",
      "had got",
      "have got",
      "will have",
      "has"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 250,
    question: "Choose the right form of the verb “to have”: Our students … mistakes in spelling.",
    answer: "have",
    options: [
      "is having",
      "had had",
      "have",
      "has",
      "are having",
    ]
  },
  
  {
    numb: 251,
    question: "Choose the right form of the verb in Present Simple: They …many official letters every day",
    answer: "receive",
    options: [
      "received",
      "is receiving",
      "receives",
      "receive",
      "are receiving",
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 252,
    question: "Choose the right form of the verb in Present Simple: The Banks usually … at 9 o’clock.",
    answer: "open",
    options: [
      "is opened",
      "has opened",
      "open",
      "opens",
      "are opening",
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 253,
    question: "Choose the right form of the verb in Present Simple: Asem … at one of the best companies.",
    answer: "works",
    options: [
      "has worked",
      "works",
      "work",
      "worked",
      "are working",
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 254,
    question: "Choose the right form of the verb in Present Simple: We always … our mother’s birthday out of town.",
    answer: "celebrate",
    options: [
      "celebrate",
      "has celebrated",
      "is celebrating",
      "celebrated",
      "are celebrating"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 255,
    question: "Choose the right form of the verb in Present Simple: We often … these boys here.",
    answer: "meet",
    options: [
      "met",
      "meeting",
      "meet",
      "had met",
      "have been meeting",
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 256,
    question: "Choose the right form of the verb in Present Simple: … she learn German or French?",
    answer: "does",
    options: [
      "will",
      "does",
      "do",
      "have",
      "had to"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 257,
    question: "Choose the right form of the verb in Present Simple: His sisters always … me books to read.",
    answer: "give",
    options: [
      "given",
      "to give",
      "give",
      "gave",
      "give to"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 258,
    question: "Choose the right form of the verb in Present Simple: … your mother have to wake you up?",
    answer: "does",
    options: [
      "do",
      "had",
      "done",
      "does",
      "to be"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 259,
    question: "Choose the general question in Past Simple: Asel and Maira delivered the goods only in 6 months.",
    answer: "Did Asel and Maira deliver the goods in 6 months?",
    options: [
      "Did Asel and Maira deliver the goods in 6 months?",
      "Do Asel and Maira deliver the goods in 6 months?",
      "Will Asel and Maira deliver the goods in 6 months?",
      "Are Asel and Maira delivered the goods in 6 months?",
      "Had Asel and Maira delivered the goods in 6 months?"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 260,
    question: "Choose the general question in Past Simple: We asked their company to prolong the contract.",
    answer: "Did we ask their company to prolong the contract?",
    options: [
      "Do we ask their company to prolong the contract?",
      "Did we ask their company to prolong the contract?",
      "Have we asked their company to prolong the contract?",
      "Does she ask their company to prolong the contract?",
      "Are we asking their company to prolong the contract?"
    ]
  },
  
  {
    numb: 261,
    question: "Choose the general question in Past Simple: Abzal went to the USA to have talks.",
    answer: "Did Abzal go to the USA to have talks?",
    options: [
      "Has Abzal went to the USA to have talks?",
      "Is Abzal going to the USA to have talks?",
      "Did Abzal go to the USA to have talks?",
      "Does Abzal go to the USA to have talks?",
      "Was Abzal going to the USA to have talks?"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 262,
    question: "Choose the general question in Past Simple: Mr. Tom offered his help to our businessmen.",
    answer: "Did Tom offer his help to our businessmen?",
    options: [
      "Will Tom offer his help to our businessmen?",
      "Did Tom offer his help to our businessmen?",
      "Does Tom offer his help to our businessmen?",
      "Is Tom offering his help to our businessmen?",
      "Was Tom offering his help to our businessmen?"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 263,
    question: "Choose the general question in Past Simple: They signed the contract yesterday.",
    answer: "Did they sign the contract yesterday?",
    options: [
      "Were they signing the contract yesterday?",
      "Do they sign the contract today?",
      "Do they sign the contract?",
      "Had they signed the contract yesterday?",
      "Did they sign the contract yesterday?"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 264,
    question: "Choose the general question in Past Simple: The teachers discussed all questions.",
    answer: "Did the teachers discuss all questions?",
    options: [
      "Are the teachers discussing all questions?",
      "Is the teacher discussing all questions?",
      "Did the teachers discuss all questions?",
      "Do the teachers discuss all questions?",
      "Does the teacher discuss all questions?",
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 265,
    question: "Choose the general question in Past Simple: My brother graduated from the University last year.",
    answer: "Did my brother graduate from the University last year?",
    options: [
      "When did my brother graduate from the University?",
      "Did my brother graduate from the University last year?",
      "What did my brother graduate last year?",
      "Had my brother graduated from the University last year?",
      "Who graduated from the University last year?"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 266,
    question: "Choose the general question in Past Simple: Aiman moved into a new flat 3 months ago.",
    answer: "Did Aiman move into a new flat 3 months ago?",
    options: [
      "Have Aiman and her family moved into a new flat 3 months ago?",
      "Does Aiman move into a new flat?",
      "Did Aiman move into a new flat 3 months ago?",
      "Has Aiman moved into a new flat 3 months ago?",
      "Aiman moved into a new flat 3 months ago, didn’t she?"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 267,
    question: "Choose the general question in Past Simple: They went to the theatre last week.",
    answer: "Did they go to the theatre last week?",
    options: [
      "Had they gone to the theatre last week?",
      "Does he go to the theatre?",
      "Did they go to the theatre last week?",
      "Do they go to the theatre?",
      "When did they go to the theatre?"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 268,
    question: "Choose the general question in Past Simple: My brother worked very hard.",
    answer: "Did my brother work very hard?",
    options: [
      "Does my brother work very hard?",
      "Did my brother work very hard?",
      "Does my sister work very hard?",
      "Whose brother worked very hard?",
      "When did he work?"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 269,
    question: "Choose the negative form: They will study History next term.",
    answer: "They will not study History next term",
    options: [
      "They do not study History this term",
      "They had not studied History last term",
      "They did not study History last term",
      "They have not studied History recently",
      "They will not study History next term"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 270,
    question: "Choose the negative form: They worked at the factory last year.",
    answer: "They did not work at the factory last year",
    options: [
      "They don’t work at the firm",
      "They had not worked at the factory last year",
      "They did not work at the factory last year",
      "They will not work at the factory next year",
      "They had not to work at the factory last year"
    ]
  },
  
  {
    numb: 271,
    question: "Choose the negative form: I visited my uncle yesterday.",
    answer: "I didn’t visit my uncle yesterday",
    options: [
      "I haven’t visited my uncle",
      "I didn’t visit my uncle yesterday",
      "I don’t visit my uncle",
      "I hadn’t visited my uncle yesterday",
      "I couldn’t visit my uncle yesterday"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 272,
    question: "Choose the negative form: We shall see you tomorrow.",
    answer: "We shall not see you tomorrow",
    options: [
      "We shall be able to see you tomorrow",
      "We did not see you yesterday",
      "He does not see you",
      "We aren’t to see you tomorrow",
      "We shall not see you tomorrow"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 273,
    question: "Choose the negative form: He worked at this shop last year.",
    answer: "He didn’t work at this shop last year",
    options: [
      "He will not work at this shop",
      "He isn’t working at this shop",
      "He didn’t work at this shop last year",
      "He hadn’t worked at that shop last year",
      "We hadn’t been working at that shop last year"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 274,
    question: "Find the general question: He is in Taraz.",
    answer: "Is he in Taraz?",
    options: [
      "Will he be in Taraz?",
      "Has he gone to Taraz?",
      "Is he in Taraz?",
      "Was he in Taraz?",
      "Can he be in Taraz?"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 275,
    question: "Find the general question: She has a fountain pen.",
    answer: "Has she a fountain pen?",
    options: [
      "What has she?",
      "Has she a fountain pen?",
      "Did she have a fountain pen?",
      "Had she or he a fountain pen?",
      "Can she have a fountain pen?"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 276,
    question: "Find the general question: His father was a doctor.",
    answer: "Was his father a doctor?",
    options: [
      "Has his father a doctor?",
      "Was his father a doctor?",
      "Will his father be a doctor?",
      "Is his father a doctor?",
      "What is his father?"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 277,
    question: "Find the general question: The weather will be fine tomorrow.",
    answer: "Will the weather be fine tomorrow?",
    options: [
      "When will the weather be fine?",
      "What will be fine tomorrow?",
      "The weather will be fine tomorrow, won’t it?",
      "Will the weather be fine tomorrow?",
      "Is the weather fine today?"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 278,
    question: "Find the general question: He can swim well.",
    answer: "Can he swim well?",
    options: [
      "Will he swim well?",
      "Is he swimming well?",
      "Can he swim well?",
      "He swims well, doesn’t he?",
      "Would he swim well?"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 279,
    question: "Choose the negative form: They will study English next year.",
    answer: "They will not study English next year.",
    options: [
      "They do not study English this year.",
      "They have not studied English recently.",
      "They had not studied English last year.",
      "They did not study English last year.",
      "They will not study English next year."
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 280,
    question: "Choose the negative form: They worked here last year.",
    answer: "They did not work here last year",
    options: [
      "They will not work at the here next year",
      "They did not work here last year",
      "They don’t work here",
      "They had not worked here last year",
      "They had not to work here last year"
    ]
  },
  
  
  {
    numb: 281,
    question: "Choose the negative form: I visited my parents yesterday.",
    answer: "I didn’t visit my parents yesterday",
    options: [
      "I don’t visit my parents",
      "I haven’t visited my parents",
      "I didn’t visit my parents yesterday",
      "I hadn’t visited my yesterday parents",
      "I couldn’t visit my parents yesterday"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 282,
    question: "Choose the right translation: двадцать второй.",
    answer: "the twenty-second",
    options: [
      "twenty-two",
      "the twentieth",
      "twelve",
      "thirty",
      "the twenty-second"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 283,
    question: "Choose the right form of the personal or possessive pronouns: … friend is a manager.",
    answer: "his",
    options: [
      "she",
      "his",
      "him",
      "it",
      "they"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 284,
    question: "Choose the right form of the personal or possessive pronouns: … family is very big.",
    answer: "Their",
    options: [
      "she",
      "me",
      "Their",
      "they",
      "them"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 285,
    question: "Choose the right form of the personal or possessive pronouns: I have a sister …name is Jane.",
    answer: "her",
    options: [
      "they",
      "her",
      "she",
      "he",
      "him",
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 286,
    question: "Choose the right form of the personal or possessive pronouns: We have got a modern cottage. …cottage is large.",
    answer: "our",
    options: [
      "I",
      "them",
      "us",
      "they",
      "our"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 287,
    question: "Choose the right form of the personal or possessive pronouns: This bag is… .",
    answer: "mine",
    options: [
      "me",
      "he",
      "mine",
      "I",
      "you"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 288,
    question: "Choose the right form of the verb “to have”: My sisters … two flats and my aunt … three flats.",
    answer: "have, has",
    options: [
      "have, have",
      "have, has",
      "has, has",
      "has, have",
      "had, has"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 289,
    question: "Choose the right variant: There are (неcколько) students in the room.",
    answer: "a few",
    options: [
      "many",
      "little",
      "a few",
      "much",
      "nowhere"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 290,
    question: "Choose the right variant: …there anybody in the office?",
    answer: "is",
    options: [
      "is",
      "do",
      "am",
      "are",
      "nothing"
    ]
  },
  
  {
    numb: 291,
    question: "Choose the right variant: There was (немного) tea in the glass.",
    answer: "a little",
    options: [
      "many",
      "nothing",
      "a little",
      "much",
      "nowhere"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 292,
    question: "Choose the right variant: There are (много) children in the streets.",
    answer: "many",
    options: [
      "little",
      "a little",
      "much",
      "many",
      "small"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 293,
    question: "Choose the right variant: There is no place like…",
    answer: "home",
    options: [
      "museum",
      "home",
      "countryside",
      "village",
      "cottage"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 294,
    question: "Find the sentence in Future Simple:",
    answer: "He will be there at eight",
    options: [
      "When are you going to have a party at home?",
      "Nick gets up very early",
      "He will be there at eight",
      "Do you often go to see your friends?",
      "I think it is the largest in our district"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 295,
    question: "Find the sentence in Future Simple:",
    answer: "We shall have a lot of work to do tomorrow",
    options: [
      "Helen gives private lessons",
      "We shall have a lot of work to do tomorrow",
      "I watched the young girl playing the piano",
      "Did you notice her go out?",
      "Now he belongs to the ages"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 296,
    question: "Find the sentence in Future Simple:",
    answer: "The winter holidays will begin on the 25th of January",
    options: [
      "I like to be out-of-doors",
      "We reached the airport early in the morning",
      "It happened during the Great Patriotic War",
      "The winter holidays will begin on the 25th of January",
      "He lived in Kiev five years ago"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 297,
    question: "Find the sentence in Future Simple:",
    answer: "He’ll finish the work if you help him",
    options: [
      "My parents have been killed",
      "He’ll finish the work if you help him",
      "Do you always get up at the same time?",
      "Let me watch TV tonight",
      "Her parents live in Astana"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 298,
    question: "Find the sentence in Future Simple:",
    answer: "I’ll be tomorrow morning",
    options: [
      "Do you often get letters from your friends?",
      "My sister left her Institute two years ago",
      "It often rains here in autumn",
      "My working day lasts eight hours",
      "I’ll be tomorrow morning"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 299,
    question: "Find the sentence in Future Simple:",
    answer: "What will you do after you graduate?",
    options: [
      "Is the teacher speaking English?",
      "What will you do after you graduate?",
      "I see nothing there.",
      "She has some English books.",
      "May I come in?"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 300,
    question: "Find the disjunctive question:",
    answer: "You study English, don’t you?",
    options: [
      "Do you speak English?",
      "Are they working now?",
      "Do you know English or German?",
      "You study English, don’t you?",
      "Will you help me?"
    ]
  },   
 




  //     {
  //    numb: 5,
  //    question: "quest",
  //    answer: "correct",
  //    options: [
  //      "option",
  //      "option",
  //      "option",
  //      "option",
  //      "option"
  //    ]
  //  },   
       
  
  
    
  
  
  
  
  ];